A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, RG 5 Program Files, Subgroup Grant Files FA1795
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Community Partners Program, 1998-2012; 6; 20.89 Cubic Feet 55 letter document boxes
  - Amherst H. Wilder Foundation, 20040160, 2004 December 7-2005 December 7 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    20040160 for $78,000, Amherst H. Wilder Foundation. To facilitate a visioning and planning process that creates a community-wide agenda for strategic growth.
  - Bellefonte YMCA 20040196, 2004 November 1-2005 October 1 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 3867
    20040196 for $50,000, Bellefonte YMCA. To plan for the establishment of the Bellefonte Family Resource.
  - Dayton's Bluff Neighborhood Housing Services, 20030293, 2003 December 9-2005 November 30 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    Knight File Number - 3870
    20030293 for $55,000, Dayton's Bluff Neighborhood Housing Services. For an assistance program for first-time homebuyers and for predevelopment planning south of the new Payne/Phalen intersection.
  - Detroit Symphony Orchestra, 20030307, 2003 December 9-2005 December 9 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 3871
    20030307 for $250,000, Detroit Symphony Orchestra. For the Community Arts Partnership Program.
  - Euell A. Wilson Center, 20030332, 2003 December 9-2005 December 9 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 3872
    20030332 for $100,000, Euell A. Wilson Center. To expand an arts appreciation and education program for at-risk youth between 10 and 18 years of age during after-school hours.
  - Families of Flight 93, Inc., 20040099, 2004 June 15-2005 June 15 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 3873
    20040099 for $500,000, Families of Flight 93, Inc. For an open, international competition to design the Flight 93 National Memorial in Somerset County, PA.
  - Fayette County Public Schools, 20030323, 2003 December 9-2005 December 9 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 3874
    20030323 for $24,500, Fayette County Public Schools. To plan the implementation of a centrally located, full-day preschool serving all four-year-old children in Fayette County.
  - Greater Twin Cities United Way, 20030303, 2003 December 9-2005 December 9 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    Knight File Number - 3877
    20030303 for $100,000, Greater Twin Cities United way. To improve oral health for Latino and Hmong children ages birth to five by providing culturally competent outreach, education, dental screenings and dental treatment services.
  - Greater Miami Neighborhood, 20030187, 2003 December 9-2005 December 9 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    Knight File Number - 4251
    Greater Miami Neighborhood, 20030187. For the creation of a Homeownership Development Program and enhancement of the homeownership education and financial literacy programs for the East Little Havana community.
  - Joint Ramsey County Interagency, 20030305, 2003 December 9-2005 December 9 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    Knight File Number - 3878
    20030305 for $180,000, Joint St. Paul and North suburban Ramsey Interagency early Intervention committee (IEIC). For project KEEP (Keep early experiences positive), an initiative designed to provide early prevention and intervention services for young children with behavioral and mental health challenges.
  - The Lynnwood Foundation, 20040047, 2002 December 10-2005 December 10 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 3881
    20040047 for $100,000. The Lynnwood Foundation. For a large-scale citizen-engagement process to create a united policy agenda for all children in Mecklenburg County.
  - Mexicantown Community Development Corp., 20030179, 2003 December 9-2005 December 9 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 3884
    20030179 for $700,000, Mexicantown community development corporation. To expand the business incubator program as part of the new Mexicantown International Welcome Center, Mercado and Public Plaza.
  - National Inventors Hall of Fame, 20030221, 2003 December 9-2005 December 11 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 3889
    20030221 for $91,700, National Inventors Hall of Fame. To implement inquiry-based science and technology after-school and summer enrichment programs at Simon Perkins Middle School.
  - Northeast Entrepreneur Fund, 20040280, 2004 September 14-2005 September 14 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    Knight File Number - 3891
    20040280 for $15,000, Northeast Entrepreneur Fund. To support planning for the Arrowhead Entrepreneur Development System to foster an entrepreneurial spirit and to grow more entrepreneurs in northeastern Minnesota.
  - Public Library of Charlotte and Mecklenburg County, 20020367, 2002 December 10-2005 June 30 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 3915
    20020367 for $207,000, Public Library of Charlotte and Mecklenburg County. To implement a neighborhood teacher program that trains parents and other caregivers of young Latino children in six Charlotte neighborhoods to use reading practices that promote emergent literacy.
  - The Saint Paul Foundation, 20030300, 2003 December 9-2005 December 9 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 3916
    20030300 for $75,000, The Saint Paul Foundation. For a loan guarantee pool in the Opportunity Housing Investment Fund.
  - Success by Six, 20030334, 2003 December 9-2005 December 9 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 3917
    20030334 for $167,000, Success by Six. To expand a successful home-visitation program by including low-income families with children ages 3 to 5 and providing more intensive public and mental health outreach services.
  - Three Rivers Jenbe Ensemble, 20040267, 2004 November 1-2005 November 1 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 3918
    20040267 for $31,000, Three Rivers Jenbe Ensemble. To provide artistic opportunities and conduct workshops in schools and community centers in Fort Wayne's southeast-side neighborhoods.
  - Chamber of Commerce of Grand Forks and East Grand Forks, 20050260, 2005 November 1-2006 November 1 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4164
    The Chamber of Commerce of Grand Forks and East Grand Forks, 20050260, $47,500 to further the work of the Augmenting Leadership Committee and the Celebrating Success Committee.
  - Child Care Resources, 20010307, 2001 December 4-2006 December 4 (Box 89, Folder 3-5)
    Knight File Number - 4105
    Child Care Resources, 20010307, $1,885,000. For Curriculum Matters, a school readiness project.
  - Community Action Council for Lexington - Fayette, 20040003, 2003 March 9-2006 March 9 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4104
    Community Action Council for Lexington - Fayette, 20040003, $103,800. To develop and pilot-test a cultural diversity training model for early childhood educators.
  - Dade Community Foundation (now The Miami Foundation, Inc.), 20030116, 2003 September 9-2006 September 9 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4165
    Dade Community Foundation, (now The Miami Foundation, Inc.) 20030116, $400,000 for the third class of the Miami Fellows Class Initiative.
  - Duluth-Superior Area Community Foundation, 20040248, 2004 November 1-2006 November 1 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 4106
    Duluth-Superior Area Community Foundation, 20040248, $30,000. For a planning grant for the Civility Initiative.
  - Foundation for the Carolinas, 20040162, 2004 June 15-2006 June 15 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4138
    Foundation for the Carolinas, 20040162, $450,000. For a major civic engagement initiative to begin eroding barriers to interracial trust and to increase the community's participation in actively charting the future.
  - Gulf Coast Community Foundation, 20050137, 2005 September 1-2006 September 1 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4166
    Gulf Coast Community Foundation, grant #20050137, $40,000 for costs associated with the marketing and outreach of the South Mississippi Earned Income Tax Credit campaign.
  - The Trust for Public Land, 20010120, 2001 June 11-2006 June 11 (Box 97, Folder 3-6)
    Knight File Number - 4124
    The Trust for Public Land, 20010120, $2,500,000. For the Overtown and East Little Havana components of the Miami River Greenway Project.
  - Alchemy, Inc., 20040034, 2004 June 15-2007 June 15 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4231
    Alchemy, Inc., 20040034. $88,000 to provide adolescent support groups for "at-risk" male students at Simon Perkins Middle School.
  - Alchemy, Inc., 20050080, 2005 July 1-2007 July 31 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 4232
    Alchemy, Inc., 20050080. $156,000 to expand the after-school program at Perkins Middle School.
  - BioEnterprise Corporation, 20050175, 2005 September 20-2007 September 20 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4236
    BioEnterprise Corporation, 20050175. $600,000 to accelerate the growth of the bioscience industry in the greater Akron area, attracting investment dollars and creating well-paying jobs.
  - Cambodian Association of America, 20040095, 2004 June 15-2007 June 15 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 4237
    Cambodian Association of America, 20040095. $330,000 for the Cambodian Family Literacy Program at Burnett Elementary School, which provides comprehensive academic and acculturation services to Cambodian preschool children and their families.
  - Fund for our Economic Future, 20040307, 2004 December 7-2007 December 7 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 4239
    Fund for our Economic Future, 20040307. $1 million for the Fund For Our Economic Future's re-granting fund and the evaluation of the initiative.
  - Living Cities, Inc.The National Community Development Initiative (NCDI), 20060054, 2006 June 1-2007 June 1 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4222
    Living Cities, Inc.The National Community Development Initiative (NCDI), 20060054. $250,000 to support planning implementation of recommendations for rebuilding in East Biloxi (entire area east of the I-110 Connector).
  - Northeast Ohio Regional Economic Development Foundation, 20030132, 2003 September 9-2007 February 1 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4224
    Northeast Ohio Regional Economic Development Foundation, 20030132. $1.5 million partial challenge grant to take team Northeast Ohio (Team NEO) from concept to implementation phase to increase: the number and quality of job opportunities; the amount of private investment; the number of busisness inquiries in the region; and the quality and quantity of business services to existing industries in Northeast Ohio.
  - One Community, One Voice, 20040311, 2004 December 7-2007 December 7 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 4225
    One Community, One Voice, 20040311. $395,000 to help increase family involvement in seven Title One Fayette County Public Schools by providing intensive parental outreach and teacher training.
  - 1st Act Silicon Valley, 20070103, 2007 August 1-2008 July 31 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 4459
    1st Act Silicon Valley, 20070103, $125,000. To help launch a new vision for Silicon Valley by supporting development of a focused plan aimed at making downtown San Jose a more viable, fun and pedestrian-friendly place.
  - Big Brothers Big Sisters of the Sun Coast, 20040084, 2004 June 15-2008 August 1 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    Knight File Number - 4466
    Big Brothers Big Sisters of the Sun Coast, 20040084, $301,500. To continue and expand mentoring programs to children at Sara Scott Harllee Middle School and Louis R. Johnson Middle School.
  - Boys & Girls Clubs of Manatee County, 20040085, 2004 June 15-2008 June 15 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 4467
    Boys & Girls Clubs of Manatee County, 20040085, $375,000. To continue providing year-round out-of-school-time programming for students attending Sara Scott Harlee Middle School in southeastern Bradenton.
  - Child Care Coordinating Council of Detroit/Wayne County, Inc, 20050177, 2005 September 20-2008 September 20 (Box 108, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 4472
    Child Care Coordinating Council of Detroit/Wayne County, Inc, 20050177, $600,000. For a computer training program and wireless Internet service for a Knight-targeted neighborhood.
  - City of Miami, 20070222, 2007 December 1-2012 December 31 (Box 108, Folder 6)
    Knight File Number - 4473
    City of Miami, 20070222, $250,000. To provide educational opportunities to students by supporting Elevate Miami, a program that will secure computers for every sixth grader in the city of Miami.
  - College Summit, 20070239, 2007 December 1-2008 December 31 (Box 108, Folder 7)
    Knight File Number - 4474
    College Summit, 20070239, $100,000. To test an innovative program aimed at getting more high school kids to college by providing seed funding for three high schools in Miami-Dade County, with 1,000 seniors benefiting.
  - Development Communications Associates, 20060056, 2006 June 1-2008 June 1 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 4475
    Development Communications Associates, 20060056. $216,000. To assist Philadelphia, Boulder and Lexington leverage their Knight grant investments into large-scale, sustainable causes.
  - Georgia College and State University, 20030115, 2003 September 9-2008 September 9 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 4477
    Georgia College & State University, 20030115, $1.255 million. To replicate the Carrera/Children's Aid Society teen pregnancy prevention program, a long-term holistic intervention, with a cohort of 30 youth in Milledgeville.
  - Georgia College and State University, 20030115 - The High Achievers: A Carerra Model Program (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation, 20040090, 2004 June 15-2008 June 15 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4508
    Local Initiatives Support Corporation, 20040090, $800,000 to design, coordinate, and implement a comprehensive community development strategy in three target neighborhoods.
  - Miami-Dade College, 20030117, 2003 September 9-2008 September 9 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 4484
    Miami-Dade College, 20030117, $400,000. To assist 20 low-income families with purchasing homes in the Villages of St. Agnes in Overtown and to create a revolving loan fund at the Housing Foundation.
  - Miami-Dade County Public Schools, 20050281, 2005 December 1-2008 November 30 (Box 111, Folder 2-3)
    Knight File Number - 4485
    Miami-Dade County Public Schools, 20050281, $360,000. For the Parent Academy.
  - Miami-Dade County Department of Cultural Affairs, 20070035, 2007 April 1-2008 June 30 (Box 111, Folder 4-5)
    Knight File Number - 4486
    Miami-Dade County Department of Cultural Affairs, 20070035, $125,000. To encourage diverse, young audiences in Miami to attend arts and cultural events by learning how to reach them with messages about performances and discounted tickets.
  - Mississippi Gulf Coast Community College, 20040083, 2004 June 15-2008 December 31 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4488
    Mississippi Gulf Coast Community College, 20040083, $305,000. To pilot the Dream of Prosperity project, providing educational financial assistance and support services to 25 low-income families toward completion of a one-or two-year education and/or work-training program.
  - OneCommunity, 20070156, 2007 October 1-2008 February 28 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 4492
    OneCommunity, 20070156, $350,000. To plan and design the creation of a Knight Center for universal access and broadband innovation.
  - Suited for Success, 20050084, 2005 July 1-2008 July 31 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4498
    Suited for Success, 20050084, $334,800. For job readiness programs in Overtown and East Little Havana.
  - The University of North Carolina at Charlotte, 20050208, 2005 October 1-2008 October 1 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4504
    The University of North Carolina at Charlotte, 20050208, $225,000. To educate local newspaper editors and reporters in the 14-county Charlotte region about open space conservation and land-use planning.
  - Vera Institute of Justice, 20050076, 2005 June 1-2008 June 1 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 4506
    Vera Institute of Justice, 20050076, $225,000. To develop tools and support efforts by the Mecklenburg County District Attorney's Office and two others to ensure racial fairness in the prosecutorial process.
  - Volunteer Services of Manatee County, 20060158, 2006 December 1-2008 December 1 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4505
    Volunteer Services of Manatee County, 20060158, $142,000. To raise community awareness and action on local issues by launching Knight Youth Voice, a program that adds a student journalism component to an innovative youth community service model.
  - Arts United of Greater Fort Wayne. 20060113, 2006 September 1-2009 September 1 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 4691
    Arts United of Greater Fort Wayne. 20060113, $750,000. To help Fort Wayne embrace "New Hoosiers" by increasing the community's understanding and appreciation of other cultures through a process that strengthens the development of arts organization in culturally diverse, underserved communities in Fort Wayne.
  - Bradenton Downtown Development Authority, 20070236, 2007 December 1-2009 May 31 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4692
    Bradenton Downtown Development Authority, 20070236, $234,000. To help form a broad-based, lead cultural organization through support of the Bradenton Culture and Business Alliance
  - Coastal Carolina University, 20040315, 2004 December 7-2009 December 7 (Box 117, Folder 1-2)
    Knight File Number - 4695
    Coastal Carolina University, 20040315, $750,000. To develop and pilot Coastal Alliance for Community Engagement, a program to recruit, train and mobilize volunteers while deepening their connections to the community.
  - Community Foundation for Palm Beach and Martin Counties, 20070089, 2006 December 1-2009 December 1 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4698
    Community Foundation for Palm Beach and Martin Counties, 20070089, $507,584. To test the concept of a community foundation providing grant support services to Knight Foundation by having the community foundation serving Palm Beach take on this role for the balance of 2007, with an emphasis on civic leadership.
  - Chapman Partnership aka Community Partnership for Homeless, 20060163, 2006 December 1-2009 December 1 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 4697
    Community Partnership for Homeless, 20060163, $250,000. To sustain Community Partnership's ability to provide housing and supportive services to homeless individuals and families in Miami-Dade County. Note: 7/12 Organization name change from Community Partnership for Homeless to Chapman Partnership. Note: Includes a confidential assessment, prepared by McKinsey & Company, "Replicating CPH's Success in Helping Homeless People", September 2007.
  - Fifty over Fifty, Inc., 20060118, 2006 October 1-2009 October 31 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4700
    Fifty over Fifty, Inc., 20060118, $100,000. To fund the first two years of the newly-created 2007/2008 Knight New Works Award (NWA), which will showcase new works of high artistic merit in the visual or performing arts in Miami.
  - Generation Engage, 20070077, 2007 June 1-2009 March 31 (Box 118, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 4701
    Generation Engage, 20070077, $246,300. To engage Charlotte-area young adults in the democratic process by launching an innovative program that brings political figures to their attention using a variety of technologies.
  - Mercer University, 20080052, 2008 June 1-2009 March 31 (Box 118, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 4704
    Mercer University, 20080052, $250,000. To underwrite the development of a 5 year business plan for the potential College Hill Alliance, marketing support for Beall's Hill neighborhood and start-up funding for College Hill Corridor programs.
  - Mercer University, 20060154, 2008 June 1-2009 March 31 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 4705
    Mercer University, 20060154, $100,000. To expand the Mercer Home Ownership Program in Beall's Hill.
  - Performing Arts Center Foundation of Greater Miami, 20060061, 2006 July 1-2009 July 1 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4707
    Performing Arts Center Foundation of Greater Miami, 20060061, $6,820,000. For the new Miami Performing Arts Center and to name the concert hall in honor of John S. and James L. Knight. Also included are shop drawings for the Arsht Center Marquee signs.
  - Philadelphia Workforce Investment Board Inc., 20070091, 2007 July 1-2009 July 31 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    Knight File Number - 4708
    Philadelphia Workforce Investment Board Inc., 20070091, $535,000. To improve Philadelphia's educational attainment rankings and workforce competitiveness by systematically re-enrolling college drop-outs through the launch of Graduate! Philadelphia (G!P).
  - Philadelphia Youth Network, Inc., 20070114, 2007 September 1-2009 September 1 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    Knight File Number - 4709
    Philadelphia Youth Network, Inc., 20070114, $230,000. To reinvent how Philadelphia addresses concurrent crises of idle youth, low labor force participation, and a rising high school dropout rate by facilitaing an extensive plan to reform, expand, and finance Career and Technical Education in the schools.
  - Prime Time Palm Beach County, 20040165, 2004 September 14-2009 September 14 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4710
    Prime Time Palm Beach County, 20040165, $4,200,000. To improve the capacity of community-based out-of-school-time youth service providers to provide quality programming for middle school-age youth in targeted areas of Palm Beach County.
  - Tubman African American Museum, Inc., 20070212, 2007 December 1-2009 November 30 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    Knight File Number - 4711
    Tubman African American Museum, Inc.,20070212, $241,000. To help a key local institution succeed by providing technical and project management support for a critical capital campaign.
  - Tubman African American Museum, Inc., 20070212 - Realizing the Dream (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - United Way of Southeastern Pennsylvania, 20030192, 2003 December 9-2009 January 31 (Box 121, Folder 1-3)
    Knight File Number - 4713
    United Way of Southeastern Pennsylvania, 20030192, $2,500,000. To implement an emergent literacy curriculum in 15 child care sites in North and West Philadelphia, improve literacy teaching skills and provide family literacy support for parents.
  - University of Miami, 20080240, 2008 December 16-2009 December 31 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4714
    University of Miami, 20080240, $150,000. To grow Miami's reputation as a gathering place for thought and discussion by supporting the Global Business Forum at the University of Miami in 2009.
  - Waccamaw Community Foundation, 20080121, 2008 September 15-2009 December 31 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    Knight File Number - 4718
    Waccamaw Community Foundation, 20080121, $290,000. To seed the development of a regional leadership network through a pilot program of the American Leadership Forum.
  - Go Kids, Inc., 20040168, 2004 September 14-2010 December 10 (Box 125, Folder 3-4)
    Knight File Number - 4839
    Go Kids, Inc., 20040168, $2,285,000 to form a five-agency alliance that will provide coordinated services to children, families and child care providers and improve families' connections to neighborhood-based developmental and economic supports.
  - Levine Museum of the New South, 20070158, 2007 September 16-2010 March 31 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    Knight File Number - 4842
    Levine Museum of the New South, 20070158, $400,000, to stimulate a community conversation around the multiple cultural traditions in Charlotte through the Newcomer Project.